准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
妈妈危机
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
这是什么意思  章鱼哥先生
What's the meaning of this, Mr. Squidward?
别问我
Don't ask me
去问海绵宝宝
Ask SpongeBob
妈  可以不用削蟹黄堡的皮的
Mom, you don't need to cut the crust off the Krabby Patty
这是在做快餐
We are making fast food
爱要慢慢来  乖儿子
Love takes time, darling
把番茄给我
Now hand me a tomato
我来把它雕成玫瑰装饰
so I can carve it into a rose garnish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
这到底是怎么回事
What in blue blazes is going on in--
海绵太太好
Hello, Mrs. SquarePants
你好啊  尤金
Well, hello, Eugene
我在学做蟹黄堡
I'm learning how to make Krabby Patties
真可爱
How lovely
我能借用一下你儿子吗
May I borrow your son for just a moment?
到底怎么回事  小子
What is going on here, boy-o?
你妈怎么会在厨房里
Why is your mother in the kitchen?
你看看外面的客人
Just take a look at that crowd
所以我以后再也不出来堂食了
This is why I never go out to eat anymore
你妈不关我蟹堡王的事
Your mommy has no business at my business
送她回家去
Send her home
可是蟹老板
But Mr. Krabs
官方员工日历上面写着今天是
the official employee calendar says it's
带妈妈上班日
Bring Your Mom to Work Day
妈妈日
可惜我忘了
Too bad I forgot
实在是太糟糕了
Boy, that would have been awful
想到我妈一来会出啥乱就让我害怕
It shivers me timbers to think
what a disaster my mom would make if she was here
大家放心
Don't you worry, fellas
我把你们的妈也请来了
I invited your moms too
什么
What?
你可真贴心啊  海绵宝宝
How thoughtful of you, SpongeBob
来都来了
Well, we're here
那就别闹了  给我看看你办的正事
so stop your horseplay and show me what you do
妈  你把我脸都丢光了
Mother, you're embarrassing me
我不知道你是在笑什么  尤金
I don't know what you're chuckling about, Eugene
放眼望去全都是在浪费钱
There's wasted money everywhere I look
上次换炸锅里的油是什么时候
When was the last time you changed the oil in this fryer?
每天都换
We change it every day, ma'am
浪费
Waste
只能一年一换
Should be but once a year
用真番茄做的番茄酱
Real tomato ketchup
浪费
Waste
你厕所里的厕纸肯定是双层的吧
I bet in your latrine you use two-ply toilet paper
只用单层的
We use one-ply
搞得跟纸是树上长的一样
As if it grows on trees
浪费
Waste
应该得用半层的
It should be half-ply
利润要想节节攀升
Your profits would be much higher
就不准花钱大手大脚
if you stopped spending willy-nilly
好的  老妈
Yes, Mama
别忘了要多笑  儿子
Remember to smile, son
我的餐呢
Where's my food?
抱歉耽搁了  先生
I'm sorry for the delay, sir
你的餐马上就到
Your order will be up soon
我又没要你不鄙视客人了
I didn't say lose your disdain
而且也别瘫着了
And don't slouch
会伤到脊椎
You'll ruin your spine
我可是无脊椎动物  老妈
I'm an invertebrate, Mother
不许顶嘴
And no back talk
好  老妈
Yes, Mother
这鄙视就挺好
Nice disdain
但给客人鄙视就够了
But save it for the customers
老头简金斯的餐好了
Order up for Old Man Jenkins
一份去皮蟹黄堡  加一份配菜沙拉
One Krabby Patty with crust removed and one side salad
我点的是薯条  不是沙拉
I ordered fries, not a salad
薯条就在沙拉里面
The fries are in the salad
那我尝尝看
Okay, I'll try it
单纯只是饿了才勉强吃
But only 'cause I'm so hungry
让我想起了我妈在我小时候的厨艺
It reminds me of my mother's cooking when I was but a boy
梦回童年让我好开心
I'm filled with childish glee
大家的餐我都做好了
I made everyone's orders
我妈不懂快餐
My mom doesn't understand fast food--
但我懂
not the way I do
她做蟹黄堡要做大半天
Her cooking takes forever
是因为她在里面加了爱
because she adds love
你是说这个蟹黄堡里没有爱吗
You mean there's no love in this Krabby Patty?
现在我只能吃出来快
Now all I taste is the fast
我要求退钱
I demand a refund
给我一点爱
Give me some love
退钱
我也要
Yeah, me too
都够了
Okay, that's enough
不准退钱
There'll be no refunds
这里面可是有爱的
You see, there is love here
我对你们钱的爱
My love for your money
你们应该不会拆散我们吧
You don't want to break us up, do ya?
把钱还回来
Give me my money back
要爱餐
不要快餐
爱去哪了
Where's the love?
我们儿子很明显上班不用功
Clearly, our sons aren't working hard enough
相信我的话  最失望的明明就是我们
Believe me when I say
no one is more disappointed than we
他们的妈
their mothers
我还以为我们教导有方
We thought we taught them better
为了避免大乱
To avert this disaster
我们要接手蟹堡王
we're going to take over the restaurant
给我们儿子做正确的示范
and show our boys how it's done
可是老妈
But Mama
闭嘴
Zip it
你们三个去羞羞脸墙角面壁思过
And to the shame corner with you three
羞羞脸墙角
现在来把这里打理干净吧
Now time to spruce this place up
妈妈王
家常菜
妈妈王家常菜
"Mama Krabs Home-style Cooking"?
一定会出大乱子
This is gonna be a disaster
看看她们对我蟹堡王怎么了
Look at what they did to me restaurant
这里看着很有家的感觉
I think the place looks homey
真想要家的感觉  还不如待家里
If I wanted "homey," I'd stay at home
她们这样会花掉我不少钱
This is costing me a fortune
海绵太太早就把这些
Actually, Mrs. SquarePants had all this stuff
都放她船的后备箱了
in the trunk of her boat
好妈妈有备无患
A mother is always prepared
我们几家的妈到最后肯定都会崩溃
Eventually, our moms will crash and burn
然后我们就夺回蟹堡王
And then we'll reclaim the Krusty Krab
那看来马上就能夺回来了
Looks like it's gonna happen sooner than later
看看谁来了
Look who just arrived
海霸王
Bubble Bass
每个妈妈的噩梦
Every mom's nightmare
海海  你把娃娃落在船上了
Bubby, you forgot your doll on the boat
妈
Mom
那是手办  不是娃娃
It's an action figure, not a doll
完蛋了
We're doomed
欢迎光临妈妈王
Welcome to Mama Krabs'
这边请
Right this way
这是你们的菜单
Here's your menus
有意思
Interesting
倒要看看
We shall see
新来的老板能不能遭得住我挑三拣四
if this new management can stand up to my scrutiny
给我全都来一
I will have one of every--
咱俩都来一份早间特餐
We'll both have the early-bird special
妈  我要去打汽水
Mother, I'm going to get a soda
妈
Mom
汽水的吸管很危险
Soda straws are dangerous
容易把眼睛戳出来
You'll put your eye out
换用这个喝
Use this instead
我是说
I mean, uh
太丢脸了
so embarrassing
上菜了
Here you go
两份蟹黄煲菜
Two Krabby Patty casseroles
切成小块  可以一口一个
I even cut it into bite-sized pieces
我家儿子就喜欢这么吃
That's just how my boy likes it
请慢用
Enjoy
那个妈宝男果然喜欢这里
Of course that mama's boy would like it here
你们看
Guys, look
大家好像都很喜欢这里
It seems like everyone is liking it here
甜蜜的家
你脸上有点脏
You've got some smudge
小费
谢谢
Danke
真不敢相信
I don't believe it
居然成功了
They're a success
那当然了
Well, of course they are
看她们干活多卖力
Look how hard they're working
看咱妈干活  感觉心里很不好受
I actually feel kind of guilty
seeing them do all the work
太可悲了
How pathetic
你们三个很明显不懂
You three clearly don't know
要怎么领略母亲的溺爱
how to appreciate
the smothering embrace of motherly love
那你有什么意见
And what do you suggest?
蟹堡王有地下室吗
Are these premises equipped with a basement?
我们到了
All right, here we are
各位  隆重介绍成年子女孤堡
Gentlemen, I present
the fortress of solitude for adult children
这就是个堆满垃圾的地下室
It's a junk-filled basement
你看到的是垃圾
You see junk
我看到的
I see--
是休闲大厅
A hangout lounge
答对了
Correct
总比羞羞脸墙角强
Well, it's better than the shame corner
大概吧
I guess
在这可以爱咋打发时间就咋打发
Down here, you can spend your time
doing whatever you want
看漫画  打电玩
Reading comics, playing video games
上网瞎骂
complaining on the Internet
你的生活选择太烂了
Your life choices are lame
不过总体概念我喜欢
but I like the overall concept
而且你们妈就在楼上
And with your mother upstairs
点心随叫随到
snacks are just a holler away
我妈就爱做点心
My mom loves to make snacks
你还有什么要传授的
What else can you teach us
很会偷懒的智者
oh wise sage of the slacker ways?
可惜我马上就要走了
Alas, my time with you is at an end
我一直都很乖
I have been a good boy
而且我妈要带我去吃冰淇淋
and my mother is taking me for ice cream
倒计时三二一
in three, two, one
我准备好去吃冰淇淋了  老妈
I'm ready for my ice cream, Mommy
姐妹再见
Bye, girls
欢迎下次再来  听见了吧
Come back soon, you hear
那看来可以试试看
Well, I guess we can give it a try
妈
Mo-om
妈  玉米片
Mom, nachos
小心堡垒
Watch the fort
妈
Mom
老妈
Hey, Ma
老妈  老妈
Mommy, Mommy
我从来都没睡得这么香过
I've never slept better in me life
昨晚有种梦回童年的感觉
Last night made me feel like a kid again
原来这就是童年的感觉
So that's what it's like to have a childhood
你们是我这位小朋友最好的朋友
You guys are the best buddies a kid could ever have
我饿了
I'm hungry
妈  早餐
Mom, breakfast
感觉哪里不对劲
Guys, I think something's wrong
确实
Agreed, lad
最好去看一下
We better go check
好耶
Oh, yeah
万岁
Booyah
怎么回事
What in tarnation?
这群懒鬼都谁啊
Who are these bums?
小朋友
Hey, kids
你来了啊  尤金
There you are, Eugene
给我做个你一直说的那个蟹黄堡
Go fix me one of those Krabbity Patties
you're always going on about
爸
Dad?
对了
That's right
今天是带爸爸上班日
Today is Bring Your Dad to Work Day
爸爸日
儿子  可不可以顺带帮我续个杯
While you're up, son, could you refill my drink?
给我再来点薯片
And more chips for me, kid
蟹黄堡做好就叫我  儿子
Any time you're ready with that Krabbity Patty, son
我要妈妈
I want my mommy
宠物石头
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
宠物公园
真高兴你今天能来宠物公园  派大星
I'm glad you can come to the pet park today, Patrick
谢谢你邀请我
Well, thanks for inviting me
我等不及要看小蜗新学的魔术了
I can't wait to see Gary's new tricks
带宠物来宠物公园最好玩了
There's nothing more fun
than bringing your pet to a pet park
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
我脑袋里有东西
I got one of those head things
脑震荡
A concussion?
对
Yeah
不过还有另外一样东西
But also the other thing
想法
A thought
没错  我想带我自己的宠物
Yeah, I think I'd like to have my own pet
到宠物公园玩
to bring to the pet park
这想法就挺好
That's a great idea
就到路边的宠物店看看吧
We can stop at the pet store on the way
宠物店
里面有没有你喜欢的宠物
Do any of these pets pique your fancy?
不行
No
Nope
那个
That one
我就要那个
I want that one
那个宠物适合我
That's the pet for me
宠物公园
可以  请进
All right, go on through
站住
Hold it right there
请你提供宠物证明
I'm gonna need to see some proof of pet
好
Of course
那是石头
That's a rock
没错
Yeah
名字叫滚滚
His name is Rolly
看不出来这哪算宠物了
I don't see how this thing is a pet
来
Here
凑近一点看
Take a closer look
好
Yes
它真可爱
He's adorable
请进
Go right in
谢谢
Thanks
来吧  滚滚
Come on, Rolly
没错  就是我的牌
Yup, that's my card
滚滚
Rolly
开采晶洞  趣味多多
Geode hunting is a cracking good time
水晶石英晶格完美无缺
The perfect crystal quartz lattice
给我的收藏增添了一份精致的标本
An exquisite specimen for my collection
滚滚  你是最棒的石头了
Rolly, you're the best rock ever
怎么回事
What the devil?
好啊
By Jove
甚是壮观
Such majesty
里面的晶洞肯定不错
That must have quite the geode inside
找到你了  小伙子
Tallyho, good chap
珀西弗尔采石家  业余晶洞爱好者
Perciful Rockhound, amateur geode enthusiast
你讲话好搞笑
You talk funny
什么
What?
你说什么  滚滚
What's that, Rolly?
滚滚想要跟你玩
Rolly says he wants to play with you
去玩吧
Here you go
祝你们两个玩得开心
Have fun, you two
派大星
Hey, Patrick
滚滚呢
Where's Rolly?
它在跟那边那位搞笑八字胡老头玩
He's playing with the funny mustache man over there
好可爱
So cute
不过也玩差不多了  滚滚
But that's enough play, Rolly
滚滚
Rolly
你今天想跟大家一起玩
You want to play with everyone today
这就不玩了
Done already?
谁是乖石头
Who's a good boy?
派大星  也许得走了
Patrick, maybe we should leave
行啊  海绵宝宝
Good idea, SpongeBob
反正大家都睡着了
Everybody here is sleeping anyway
走了  滚滚
Come on, Rolly
我一定要敲开那颗石头
I will tear that rock asunder
今天真好玩
What a fun day
现在就来做我最爱的事情
Now it's time to do my favorite thing--
什么都不做
nothing
海胆哥与败蜗子秀  开播
It's the "Sir Urchin & Snail Fail Show"
海胆哥与败蜗子秀
你可恶
Why, you
我哪有
What'd I do?
海绵宝宝家
SquarePants residence
海绵宝宝
Oh, SpongeBob
滚滚好像不喜欢电视
I don't think Rolly likes TV
它把家都拆了
He tore up the place
你有喂过它吗
Have you been feeding him?
宠物没东西吃容易发飙
Pets get cranky if they don't get their food
没错
Oh, yeah
谢了兄弟
Thanks, buddy
没事
Of course
滚滚
Rolly
海绵宝宝说你得吃不少东西
SpongeBob said you need lots of food
还好我手上有这一大袋水泥综合点心
Good thing I had this big bag of cement mix on hand
水泥
加水即可
Just add water
好
Okay
用餐愉慢  滚滚
Bone apple teeth, Rolly
现在我得来吃午饭了
Now it's time for my lunch
我就喜欢干吃
I like it dry
滚滚  你长大了
Rolly, you got big
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
什么事
Yes?
我喂了滚滚  它就长大了
I fed Rolly, and he got big
它是要死了吗
Is he dying?
不对  你真笨
No, you silly
它可能是想去外面遛遛  上个厕所
He probably just needs a walk to go potty
不过遛它一定要牵绳
But make sure he wears his leash
好
Okay
该去遛遛了  滚滚
Time for a walk, Rolly
全世界都是你的马桶
The world is your toilet
好家伙
My word
他的石头长得好圆
How rotund his rock has grown
一定要偷到那颗圆滚滚的石子
I must pilfer that plump pebble
啥味道这么臭
What stinks?
是你啊  滚滚
It's you, Rolly
我该干什么来着
What am I supposed to do?
喂  海绵宝宝
Hi, SpongeBob
派大星
Hey, Patrick
滚滚有股垃圾馊水的味道
Rolly smells like garbage water
是对我发火了吗
Is he mad at me?
怎么会
Of course not
可以带去宠物美容店
You can take him to a groomer
把它洗干净
to freshen him up
便利
石头美容店
便利石头美容店
Conveniently Placed Rock Groomer
这边就有一家
There's one right here
谢谢海绵宝宝
Thanks, SpongeBob
你好  先生
Good day, sir
我是石头美容师
I'm the rock groomer
能不能给我那颗
May I take that
收藏价值极高的耀眼巨石呢
ample, glorious collectible rock from you?
滚滚得洗个澡
Rolly needs a bath
终于啊
At last
你坚固外表下的闪耀内心就要归我了
the glimmering contents
of your sturdy aspects shall be mine
不行
Oh, no
退后  你这怪兽
Back, you beast
已经干净了
Finished already?
滚滚  你好美啊
Rolly, you're beautiful
得跟海绵宝宝说一下
I've gotta tell SpongeBob
又打来了
Hi again
海绵宝宝  滚滚已经美得
SpongeBob, Rolly looks prettier than
比特别美的东西还美了
a really pretty thing
一定得来看一下
You gotta see him
那你就该带它参加
Well, you should bring him down
裤头村宠物秀
to the Bikini Bottom Pet Show
我跟小蜗现在就在现场
Gary and I are here now
裤头村宠物秀
太棒了
Great
不见不散
See ya there
小姐  你得洗个澡
Lady, you need a bath
裤头村宠物秀
牡蛎体育场
24号参赛者
Contestant 24
它就叫滚滚
His name is Rolly
是不是很美啊
Isn't he pretty?
它有什么才艺
What does it do?
这就表演给你看
I'll show you
派大星  加油
Go, Patrick, go
哒哒
Ta-da
看来其他参赛者
Well, it seems every other contestant
全都被淘汰了
has been eliminated
消 灭
也只能当你赢了
I suppose you win
都是默认的
by default
我们
We--
宠物冠军
赢了
did it
滚滚  你是最棒的石头
Rolly, you're the best rock--
了
Ever
蕴藏在里面的水晶珍宝总算归我了
Finally, your crystalline cache is all mine
滚滚
Rolly
不要
Oh, no
你真棒  老兄
G-g-good show, old chap
太扯了
Oh, fiddlesticks
滚滚
Rolly
我好爱你的新模样
I love your new look
原来滚滚从头到尾都是颗蛋啊
So Rolly was an egg all along
这样才叫宠物
Now that's what I call a pet